(screen whooshes)
(face logo whooshes)
- The pipeline function.
The pipeline function is
the most high level API
of the Transformers library.
It regroups together all the steps
to go from raw texts
to usable predictions.
The model used is at
the core of a pipeline,
but the pipeline also include
all the necessary pre-processing,
since the model does not
expect texts, but number,
as well as some post-processing,
to make the output of
the model human-readable.
Let's look at a first example
with the sentiment analysis pipeline.
This pipeline performs text
classification on a given input
and determines if it's
positive or negative.
Here, it attributed the positive
label on the given text,
with a confidence of 95%.
You can pass multiple
texts to the same pipeline,
which will be processed and passed
through the model together as a batch.
The output is a list of individual results
in the same order as the input texts.
Here we find the same label
and score for the first text,
and the second text is judged negative
with a confidence of 99.9%.
The zero-shot classification pipeline
is a more general
text-classification pipeline,
it allows you to provide
the labels you want.
Here we want to classify our
input text along the labels,
education, politics, and business.
The pipeline successfully recognizes
it's more about education
than the other labels,
with a confidence of 84%.
Moving on to other tasks,
the text generation pipeline will
auto-complete a given prompt.
The output is generated
with a bit of randomness,
so it changes each time you
call the generator object
on a given prompt.
Up until now, we've used
the the pipeline API
with the default model
associated to each task,
but you can use it with any
model that has been pretrained
or fine-tuned on this task.
Going on the model hub,
huggingface.co/models
you can filter the
available models by task.
The default model used in our
previous example was gpt2,
but there are many more models available,
and not just in English.
Let's go back to the
text generation pipeline
and load it with another
model, distilgpt2.
This is a lighter version of gpt2
created by the Hugging Face team.
When applying the pipeline
to a given prompt,
we can specify several arguments
such as the maximum length
of the generated texts,
or the number of sentences
we want to return,
since there is some
randomness in the generation.
Generating texts by guessing
the next word in a sentence
was the pretraining objective of GPT-2.
The fill mask pipeline is the
pretraining objective of BERT,
which is to guess the
value of masked word.
In this case, we ask the
two most likely values
for the missing words,
according to the model,
and get mathematical or
computational as possible answers.
Another task Transformers
model can perform
is to classify each word in the sentence
instead of the sentence as a whole.
One example of this is
Named Entity Recognition,
which is the task of identifying entities,
such as persons, organizations
or locations in a sentence.
Here, the model correctly
finds the person, Sylvain,
the organization, Hugging Face,
as well as the location, Brooklyn,
inside the input text.
The grouped_entities=True argument used
is to make the pipeline group together
the different words
linked to the same entity,
such as Hugging and Face here.
Another task available
with the pipeline API
is extractive question answering.
Providing a context and a question,
the model will identify the
span of text in the context
containing the answer to the question.
Getting short summaries
of very long articles
is also something the Transformers
library can help with,
with the summarization pipeline.
Finally, the last task
supported by the pipeline API
is translation.
Here we use a French/English model
found on the model hub
to get the English
version of our input text.
Here is a brief summary of all the tasks
we've looked into in this video.
Try then out through the inference widgets
in the model hub.
(screen whooshes)
(logo whooshes)