(whooshing sound)
- How to instantiate
the Transformers model?
In this video, we will
look at how we can create
and use a model from the
Transformers library.
As we've seen before,
the TFAutoModel class
allows you to instantiate
a pre-trained model
from any checkpoint on
the Hugging Face Hub.
It will pick the right
model class from the library
to instantiate the proper architecture
and load the weights of the
pre-trained model inside.
As we can see, when
given a BERT checkpoint,
we end up with a TFBertModel,
and similarly for GPT2 or BART.
Behind the scenes, this
API can take the name
of a checkpoint on the Hub,
in which case it will download and cache
the configuration file as well
as the model weights file.
You can also specify the
path to a local folder
that contains a valid configuration file
and a model weights file.
To instantiate the pre-trained model,
the TFAutoModel API will first
open the configuration file
to look at the configuration
class that should be used.
The configuration class depends
on the type of the model,
BERT, GPT2 or BART for instance.
Once it has the proper
configuration class,
it can instantiate that configuration,
which is a blueprint to know
how to create the model.
It also uses this configuration class
to find the proper model class,
which is combined with
the loaded configuration
to load the model.
This model is not yet
our pre-trained model
as it has just been initialized
with random weights.
The last step is to load the weights
from the model file inside this model.
To easily load the
configuration of a model
from any checkpoint or a folder
containing the configuration file,
we can use the AutoConfig class.
Like the TFAutoModel class,
it will pick the right configuration
class from the library.
We can also use the specific class
corresponding to a checkpoint,
but we will need to change the code
each time we want to try a
different model architecture.
As we said before, the
configuration of a model
is a blueprint that contains
all the information necessary
to create the model architecture.
For instance, the BERT model
associated with the
bert-base-cased checkpoint
has 12 layers, a hidden size of 768,
and a vocabulary size of 28,996.
Once we have the configuration,
we can create a model that
has the same architecture
as our checkpoint but
is randomly initialized.
We can then train it from scratch
like any TensorFlow model.
We can also change any
part of the configuration
by using keyword arguments.
The second snippet of code instantiates
a randomly initialized BERT model
with 10 layers instead of 12.
Saving a model once it's trained
or fine-tuned is very easy.
We just have to use the
save_pretrained method.
Here, the model will be saved in a folder
named my-bert-model inside
the current working directory.
Such a model can then be reloaded
using the from_pretrained method.
To run it to a projects model to the Hub,
check out the push (mumbles) video.
(whooshing sound)