(screen whooshing)
(sticker popping)
- Let's take a look at
word-based tokenization.
Word-based tokenization is the idea
of splitting the raw text into words
by splitting on spaces
or other specific rules,
like punctuation.
In this algorithm, each
word has a specific number
or ID attributed to it.
Here, let's has the ID 250,
do has 861, and tokenization
followed by an exclamation mark has 345.
This approach is interesting
as the model has representations
that are based on entire words.
The information held in
a single number is high,
as a word contains a lot of contextual
and semantic information.
However, this approach
does have its limits.
For example, the word dog and
the word dogs are very similar
and their meaning is close.
The word-based tokenization, however,
will attribute entirely
different IDs to these two words
and the model will therefore learn
two different embeddings
for these two words.
This is unfortunate as
we would like the model
to understand that these
words are indeed related,
and that dogs is simply the
plural form of the word dog.
Another issue with this approach,
is that there are a lot of
different words in the language.
If we want our model to understand
all possible sentences in that language,
then we will need to have an
ID for each different word.
And the total number of words,
which is also known as
the vocabulary size,
can quickly become very large.
This is an issue because each
ID is mapped to a large vector
that represents the word's meaning,
and keeping track of these mappings
requires an enormous number of weights
when the vocabulary size is very large.
If we want our models to stay lean,
we can opt for our tokenizer
to ignore certain words
that we don't necessarily need.
For example, here, when training
our tokenizer on a text,
we might want to take only
the 10,000 most frequent words
in that text.
Rather than taking all
words from in that text
or all languages words to
create our basic vocabulary.
The tokenizer will know how
to convert those 10,000 words
into numbers, but any other
word will be converted
to the out-of-vocabulary word,
or like shown here, the unknown word.
Unfortunately, this is a compromise.
The model will have the
exact same representation
for all words that it doesn't know,
which can result in a
lot of lost information
if many unknown words are present.
(screen whooshing)