(object whooshing)
- The tokenizer pipeline.
In this video, we'll look
at how a tokenizer converts
raw texts to numbers,
that a Transformer
model can make sense of,
like when we execute this code.
Here is a quick overview
of what happens inside
the tokenizer object:
first, the text is split into tokens,
which are words, parts of
words, or punctuation symbols.
Then the tokenizer adds
potential special tokens
and converts each token to
their unique respective ID
as defined by the tokenizer's vocabulary.
As we'll see, it doesn't
quite happen in this order,
but doing it like this is
better for understandings.
The first step is to split
our input text into tokens.
We use the tokenize method for this.
To do that, the tokenizer may
first perform some operations,
like lowercasing all words,
then follow a set of rules
to split the result in
small chunks of text.
Most of the Transformer models uses
a word tokenization algorithm, which means
that one given word can be split
in several tokens like tokenize here.
Look at the "Tokenization
algorithms" video link below
for more information.
The # # prefix we see in front of ize is
a convention used by Bert to indicate
this token is not the
beginning of the word.
Other tokenizers may use
different conventions however:
for instance, ALBERT tokenizers
will add a long underscore
in front of all the tokens
that added space before them,
which is a convention shared
by all sentencepiece tokenizers.
The second step of the
tokenization pipeline is
to map those tokens to
their respective IDs
as defined by the
vocabulary of the tokenizer.
This is why we need to download the file
when we instantiate a tokenizer
with the from_pretrained method.
We have to make sure
we use the same mapping
as when the model was pretrained.
To do this, we use the
convert_tokens_to_ids method.
We may have noticed
that we don't have the exact same results
as in our first slide, or not
as this looks like a list
of random numbers anyway,
in which case, allow me
to refresh your memory.
We had a the number at
the beginning and a number
at the end that are missing,
those are the special tokens.
The special tokens are added
by the prepare_for_model method
which knows the indices of this token
in the vocabulary and just
adds the proper numbers.
in the input IDs list.
You can look at the special tokens
and, more generally,
at how the tokenizer
has changed your text,
by using the decode method
on the outputs of the tokenizer object.
As for the prefix for beginning
of words/ part of words, for
special tokens vary depending
on which tokenizer you're using.
So that tokenizer uses CLS and SEP,
but the roberta tokenizer
uses HTML-like anchors
and .
Now that you know how the tokenizer works,
you can forget all those
intermediate methods,
and then you remember that
you just have to call it
on your input texts.
The output of a tokenizer don't
just contain the input IDs, however.
To learn what the attention mask is,
check out the "Batch
input together" video.
To learn about token type IDs,
look at the "Process
pairs of sentences" video.
(object whooshing)