(graphics whooshing)
- How to pre-process pairs of sentences.
We have seen how to
tokenize single sentences
and batch them together in the,
"Batching inputs together video."
If this code look unfamiliar to you,
be sure to check that video again.
Here will focus on tasks that
classify pair of sentences.
For instance, we may want to
classify whether two texts
are paraphrased or not.
Here is an example taken
from the Quora Question Pairs
dataset, which focuses on
identifying duplicate questions.
In the first pair, the two
questions are duplicates,
in the second they are not.
Another pair classification problem is
when we want to know if two sentences are
logically related or not,
a problem called natural
language inference or NLI.
In this example, taken
from the MultiNLI data set,
we have a pair of sentences
for each possible label.
Contradiction, natural or entailment,
which is a fancy way of
saying the first sentence
implies the second.
So classifying pairs of
sentences is a problem
worth studying.
In fact, in the GLUE benchmark,
which is an academic benchmark
for text classification
eight of the 10 data sets are focused
on tasks using pairs of sentences.
That's why models like BERT
are often pre-trained
with a dual objective.
On top of the language modeling objective,
they often have an objective
related to sentence pairs.
For instance, during
pretraining BERT is shown
pairs of sentences and must predict both
the value of randomly masked
tokens, and whether the second
sentence follow from the first or not.
Fortunately, the tokenizer
from the Transformers library
has a nice API to deal
with pairs of sentences.
You just have to pass
them as two arguments
to the tokenizer.
On top of the input IDs
and the attention mask
we studied already,
it returns a new field
called token type IDs,
which tells the model which tokens belong
to the first sentence,
and which ones belong
to the second sentence.
Zooming in a little bit,
here has an input IDs
aligned with the tokens
they correspond to,
their respective token
type ID and attention mask.
We can see the tokenizer
also added special tokens.
So we have a CLS token, the
tokens from the first sentence,
a SEP token, the tokens
from the second sentence,
and a final SEP token.
If we have several pairs of sentences,
we can tokenize them
together by passing the list
of first sentences, then
the list of second sentences
and all the keyword
arguments we studied already
like padding=True.
Zooming in at the result,
we can see also tokenize added padding
to the second pair sentences
to make the two outputs
the same length, and properly
dealt with token type IDs
and attention masks for the two sentences.
This is then all ready to
pass through our model.