In our other videos we talked about the basics
of fine-tuning a language model with Tensorflow
(and as always, when I refer to videos I'll link
them below). Still, can we do better? So here's
the code from our model fine-tuning video, and
while it works, we could definitely tweak a couple
of things. By far the most important thing is the
learning rate. In this video we'll talk about how
to change it, which will make your training
much more consistently successful. In fact,
there are two things we want to change about the
default learning rate for Adam. The first is that
it's way too high for our models - by default
Adam uses a learning rate of 10^-3 1 e minus 3,
which is very high for training Transformers.
We're going to start at 5 by 10^-5 5 e minus 5,
which is 20 times lower than the default. And
secondly, we don't just want a constant learning
rate - we can get even better performance if we
'decay' the learning rate down to a tiny value,
or even 0, over the course of training. That's
what this PolynomialDecay schedule thing is doing.
That name might be intimidating, especially
if you only vaguely remember what a polynomial
is from maths class. However, all we need to
do is tell it how long training is going to be,
so it decays at the right speed -
that's what this code here is doing.
We're computing how many minibatches the model
is going to see over its entire training run,
which is the size of the training set, divided
by the batch_size to get the number of batches
per epoch, and then multiplied by the
number of epochs to get the total number
of batches across the whole training run. Once
we know how many training steps we're taking,
we just pass all that information to
the scheduler and we're ready to go.
What does the polynomial decay schedule look
like? With default options, it's actually just a
linear schedule, so it looks like this - it starts
at 5e-5, which means 5 times ten to the minus 5,
and then decays down at a constant rate until
it hits zero right at the very end of training.
So why do they call it polynomial and not
linear? Because if you tweak the options,
you can get a higher-order decay schedule, but
there's no need to do that right now. Now, how
do we use our learning rate schedule? Easy,
we just pass it to Adam! You'll notice the
first time when we compiled the model,
we just passed it the string "adam".
Keras recognizes the names of common optimizers
and loss functions if you pass them as strings,
so it saves time to do that if you only want
the default settings. But we're professional
machine learners now, with our very own learning
rate schedule, so we have to do things properly.
So first we import the optimizer, then we
initialize it with our scheduler, and then
we compile the model using the new optimizer,
and whatever loss function you want - this will
be sparse categorical crossentropy if you're
following along from the fine-tuning video.
And now we have a high-performance model, ready to
go. All that remains is to fit the model just like
we did before! Remember, because we compiled the
model with the new optimizer with the new learning
rate schedule, we don't need to change anything
here. We just call fit again, with exactly the
same command as before, but now we get beautiful
training with a nice, smooth learning rate decay.