(air whooshing)
- Supercharge your PyTorch training loop
with Hugging Face Accelerate.
There are multiple setups
on which you can run your training:
it could be on CPU, GPUs, TPUs,
distributed on one machine
with several devices,
or even several machines,
often called nodes,
each with multiple devices.
On top of that, there are new tweaks
to make your training
faster or more efficient,
like mixed precision and DeepSpeed.
Each of those setups or training tweaks
requires you to change the
code of your training loop
in one way or another
and to learn a new API.
All those setups are
handled by the Trainer API,
and there are several third-party
libraries that can help.
The problem with those
is that they can feel like a black box
and that it might not be
easy to implement the tweak
to the training loop you need.
Accelerate has been designed specifically
to let you retain full control
over your training loop
and be as non-intrusive as possible.
With just four lines of code
to add to your training loop,
here shown on the example
of the training loop video,
Accelerate will handle all the setups
and training tweaks
mentioned on the first slide.
It's only one API to learn and master
instead of 10 different ones.
More specifically, you have
to import and instantiate
an accelerator object,
that will handle all the necessary code
for your specific setup.
Then you have to send it the model,
optimizer and dataloaders you are using
in the prepare method, which
is the main method to remember.
Accelerate handles device placement,
so you don't need to put your batch
on the specific device you are using.
Finally, you have to replace
the loss.backward line
by accelerator.backwardloss,
and that's all you need!
Accelerate also handles
distributed evaluation.
You can still use a
classic evaluation loop
such as the one we saw in
the training loop video,
in which case all processes
will perform the full evaluation.
To use a distributed evaluation,
you just have to adapt your
evaluation loop like this:
pass along the evaluation dataloader
to the accelerator.prepare
method, like for training.
Then you can dismiss the line
that places the batch
on the proper device,
and just before passing your predictions
and labels to your metric,
use accelerator.gather
to gather together the predictions
and labels from each process.
A distributed training script
has to be launched several
times on different processes,
for instance, one per GPU you are using.
You can use the PyTorch tools to do that
if you are familiar with them,
but Accelerate also provides an easy API
to configure your setup and
launch your training script.
In a terminal, run accelerate config
and answer the small questionnaire
to generate a configuration file
with all the relevant information,
then you can just run accelerate launch,
followed by the path to
your training script.
In a notebook, you can use
the notebook launcher function
to launch your training.
(air whooshing)