(upbeat music)
- [Instructor] In this
video, we're going to go over
the HuggingFace Model Hub navigation.
This is the huggingface.co landing page.
To access the model hub,
click on the models tab
in the upper right corner.
You should be facing this web interface,
which can be split into several parts.
On the left, you'll find categories,
which you can use to
tailor your model search.
The first category is the tasks.
Models on the hub may be used
for a wide variety of tasks.
These include natural
language processing tasks,
such as question answering
or text classification,
but it isn't only limited to NLP.
Other tasks from other
fields are also available,
such as image classification
for computer vision,
or automatic speech
recognition for speech.
The second category is the libraries.
Models on the hub usually
share one of three backbones,
PyTorch, TensorFlow, or JAX.
However, other backbones, such
as rust or ONNX also exist.
Finally, this tab can also be used
to specify from which high-level
framework the models comes.
This includes Transformers,
but it isn't limited to it.
The model hub is used to host
a lot of different frameworks models,
and we're actively looking to host
other frameworks models.
The third category is the datasets tab.
Selecting a dataset from this
tab means filtering the models
so that they were trained
on that specific dataset.
The fourth category is the languages tab.
Selecting a language from this tab
means filtering the
models so that they handle
the language selected.
Finally, the last category
allows to choose the license
with which the model is shared.
On the right, you'll
find the models available
on the model hub.
The models are ordered
by downloads by default.
When clicking on a model,
you should be facing its model card.
The model card contains
information about the model,
its description, intended
use, limitations and biases.
It can also show code snippets
on how to use the model,
as well as any relevant information;
training procedure, data processing,
evaluation results or copyrights.
This information is crucial
for the model to be used.
The better crafted a model card is,
the easier it will be for other
users to leverage your model
in their applications.
On the right of the model
card is the inference API.
This inference API can be used
to play with the model directly.
Feel free to modify the
text and click on compute
to see how would the model
behave to your inputs.
At the top of your screen
lies the model tags.
These include the model task,
as well as any other tag
that is relevant to the
categories we have just seen.
The files & versions tab
displays the architecture
of the repository of that model.
Here, we can see all the
files that define this model.
You'll see all usual
features of a Git repository:
the branches available,
the commit history
as well as the commit diff.
Three different buttons are available
at the top of the model card.
The first one shows how to use
the inference API programmatically.
The second one shows how to
train this model in SageMaker.
And the last one shows
how to load that model
within the appropriate library.
For BERT, this is transformers.
(upbeat music)