(swoosh)
- [Narrator] Hi, this
is going to be a video
about the push_to_hub API
for Tensorflow and Keras.
So, to get started, we'll
open up our notebook.
And the first thing you'll
need to do is log in to
your HuggingFace account,
for example with the
notebook login function.
So to use that, you
simply call the function,
the popup will emerge.
You will enter your username and password,
which I'm going to pull out
of my password manager here,
and you log in.
The next two cells are just
getting everything ready for training.
So we're just going to load a dataset,
we're going to tokenize that dataset,
and then we're going to
load our model and compile
it with the standard Adam optimizer.
So I'm just going to run all of those.
We'll wait a few seconds,
and everything should
be ready for training.
Okay.
So now we're ready to train.
I'm going to show you the two ways
you can push your model to the Hub.
So the first is with
the PushToHubCallback.
So a callback in Keras
is a function that's called
regularly during training.
You can set it to be called
after a certain number of steps,
or every epoch, or even just
once at the end of training.
So a lot of callbacks
in Keras, for example,
control learning rate decaying on plateau,
and things like that.
So this callback, by default,
will save your model to
the Hub once every epoch.
And that's really helpful,
especially if your training is very long,
because that means you
can resume from that save,
so you get this automatic
cloud-saving of your model.
And you can even run inference
with the checkpoints of your model
that have been uploaded by this callback.
And that means you can,
y'know, run some test inputs
and actually see how your model works
at various stages during training,
which is a really nice feature.
So we're going to add
the PushToHubCallback,
and it takes just a few arguments.
So the first argument is
the temporary directory
that files are going to be saved to
before they're uploaded to the Hub.
The second argument is the tokenizer,
and the third argument here
is the keyword argument hub_model_id.
So that's the name it's
going to be saved under
on the HuggingFace Hub.
You can also upload to
an organization account
just by adding the organization name
before the repository name
with a slash, like this.
So you probably don't have permissions
to upload to the HuggingFace organization,
if you do please file a bug
and let us know extremely urgently.
But if you do have access
to your own organization,
then you can use that same approach
to upload models to their account
instead of to your own
personal set of models.
So, once you've made your callback,
you simply add it to the callbacks list
when you're calling model.fit.
And everything is uploaded
for you from there,
there's nothing else to worry about.
The second way to upload a model, though,
is to call model.push_to_hub.
So this is more of a once-off method.
It's not called regularly during training.
You can just call this
manually whenever you want to
upload a model to the hub.
So we recommend running this
after the end of training,
just to make sure that
you have a commit message
to guarantee that this
was the final version
of the model at the end of training.
And it just makes sure that, you know,
you're working with the
definitive end-of-training model
and not accidentally using a checkpoint
from somewhere along the way.
So I'm going to run both of these cells.
And then I'm going to cut the video here,
just because training is going
to take a couple of minutes.
So I'll skip forward to the end of that,
when the models have all been uploaded,
and I'm gonna show you how you can
access the models in the Hub,
and the other things you
can do with them from there.
Okay, we're back,
and our model was uploaded.
Both by the PushToHubCallback
and also by our call to
model.push_to_hub after training.
So everything's looking good.
So now if we drop over to
my profile on HuggingFace,
and you can get there just by
clicking the profile button
in the dropdown.
We can see that the
bert-fine-tuned-cola model is here,
and was updated 3 minutes ago.
So it'll always be at
the top of your list,
because they're sorted by how
recently they were updated.
And we can start querying
our model immediately.
So the dataset we were training on
is the Glue CoLA dataset,
and CoLA is an acronym standing for
the Corpus of Linguistic Acceptability.
So what that means is the model
is being trained to decide
if a sentence is grammatically
or linguistically okay,
or if there's a problem with it.
For example, we could say,
"This is a legitimate sentence."
And hopefully it realizes that
this is in fact a legitimate sentence.
So it might take a couple of
seconds for the model to load
when you call it for the first time.
So I might cut a couple of
seconds out of this video here.
Okay, we're back.
So the model loaded and we got an output,
but there's an obvious problem here.
So these labels aren't really telling us
what categories the model
has actually assigned
to this input sentence.
So if we want to fix that,
we want to make sure the model config
has the correct names for
each of the label classes,
and then we want to upload that config.
So we can do that down here.
To get the label names,
we can get that from
the dataset we loaded,
from the features attribute it has.
And then we can create dictionaries
"id2label" and "label2id",
and just assign them to the model config.
And then we can just
push our updated config,
and that'll override the
existing config in the Hub repo.
So that's just been done.
So now, if we go back here,
I'm going to use a
slightly different sentence
because the outputs for
sentences are sometimes cached.
And so, if we want to generate new results
I'm going to use something
slightly different.
So let's try an incorrect sentence.
So this is not valid English grammar
and hopefully the model will see that.
It's going to reload here,
so I'm going to cut a
couple of seconds here,
and then we'll see what
the model is going to say.
Okay.
So the model, it's
confidence isn't very good,
because of course we
didn't really optimize
our hyperparameters at all.
But it has decided that this sentence
is more likely to be
unacceptable than acceptable.
Presumably if we tried a
bit harder with training
we could get a much lower validation loss,
and therefore the model's
predictions would be more precise.
But let's try our original sentence again.
Of course, because of the caching issue,
we're seeing that the original
answers are unchanged.
So let's try a different, valid sentence.
So let's try, "This is a
valid English sentence".
And we see that now the
model correctly decides
that it has a very high
probability of being acceptable,
and a very low probability
of being unacceptable.
So you can use this inference API
even with the checkpoints that
are uploaded during training,
so it can be very interesting to see how
the model's predictions
for sample inputs change
with each epoch of training.
Also, the model we've uploaded
is going to be accessible to you and,
if it's shared publicly, to anyone else.
So if you want to load that model,
all you or anyone else needs to do
is just to load it in either a pipeline,
or you can just load it with, for example,
TFAutoModelForSequenceClassification.
And then for the name you
would just simply pass
the path to the repo you want to upload.
Or to download, excuse me.
So if I want to use this model again,
if I want to load it from the hub,
I just run this one line of code.
The model will be downloaded.
And, with any luck, it'll be ready to
fine-tune on a different
dataset, make predictions with,
or do anything else you wanna do.
So that was a quick overview of how,
after your training or
during your training,
you can upload models to the Hub,
you can checkpoint there,
you can resume training from there,
and you can get inference results
from the models you've uploaded.
So thank you, and I hope to
see you in a future video.
(swoosh)