(air whooshing)
- How to slice and dice the dataset?
Most of the time, the data you work with
won't be perfectly prepared
for training models.
In this video, we'll
explore various features
that the datasets library
provides to clean up your data.
The datasets library provides
several built-in methods
that allow you to wrangle
your data in various ways.
In this video, we'll
see how you can shuffle
and split your data, select
the rows you're interested in,
tweak the columns,
and apply processing
functions with the map method.
Let's start with shuffling.
It is generally a good idea
to apply shuffling to your training set
so that your model doesn't learn
any artificial ordering the data.
If you wanna shuffle the whole dataset,
you can apply the appropriately
named shuffle method.
You can see an example of
this method in action here,
where we've downloaded the training split
of the squad dataset and
shuffled all the rows randomly.
Another way to shuffle the data
is to create random train and test splits.
This can be useful if you have to create
your own test splits from raw data.
To do this, you just apply
the train_test_split method
and specify how large
the test split should be.
In this example, we specify
that the test set should be 10%
of the total dataset size.
You can see that the output
of the train_test_split method
is a DatasetDict object
whose keys correspond to the new splits.
Now that we know how
to shuffle the dataset,
let's take a look at returning
the rows we're interested in.
The most common way to do this
is with the select method.
This method expects a list
or a generator of the datasets indices,
and will then return a new dataset object
containing just those rows.
If you wanna create a
random sample of rows,
you can do this by chaining the shuffle
and select methods together.
In this example,
we've created a sample of five elements
from the squad dataset.
The last way to pick out
specific rows in a dataset
is by applying the filter method.
This method checks whether each row
fulfills some condition or not.
For example, here we've
created a small lambda function
that checks whether the title
starts with the letter L.
Once we apply this function
with the filter method,
we get a subset of the data
just containing these rows.
So far, we've been talking
about the rows of a dataset,
but what about the columns?
The datasets library has two main methods
for transforming columns,
a rename_column method to
change the name of the column
and a remove_columns
method to delete them.
You can see examples of
both these methods here.
Some datasets have nested columns,
and you can expand these by
applying the flatten method.
For example, in the squad dataset,
the answers column contains a
text and answer_start field.
If we wanna promote them to
their own separate columns,
we can apply flatten as shown here.
Now of course, no discussion
of the datasets library
would be complete without
mentioning the famous map method.
This method applies a
custom processing function
to each row in the dataset.
For example, here we first define
a lowercase title function,
that simply lowercases the
text in the title column.
And then we feed that
function to the map method,
and voila, we now have lowercase titles.
The map method can also be
used to feed batches of rows
to the processing function.
This is especially useful for tokenization
where the tokenizer is backed
by the Tokenizers library,
and they can use fast multithreading
to process batches in parallel.
(air whooshing)