(whooshing sound)
(sticker popping)
- Datasets and DataFrames equals love.
Although the processing
functions of the Datasets library
will cover most of the cases
needed to train a model,
there are times when you'll
need to switch to a library
like Pandas to access
more powerful features
or high level APIs for visualization.
Fortunately, the Datasets
library is designed
to be interoperable with
libraries like Pandas,
as well as NumPy, PyTorch,
TensorFlow and JAX.
In this video, we'll take a look
at how we can quickly switch our data
to Pandas DataFrames and back.
As an example, let's
suppose we're analyzing
Supreme Court cases from Switzerland.
As usual, we download
our dataset from the hub
using the load_dataset function.
And you can see that the first
element of the training set
is an ordinary Python dictionary
with various fields of interest.
Now, suppose that before
we train any models,
we'd like to explore the data a bit.
For example, we might
be interested in knowing
which legal areas are the most common
or we might wanna know how the languages
are distributed across regions.
Answering these questions
with the native Arrow format isn't easy,
but we can quickly switch to
Pandas to get our answers.
The way this works is that by
using the set_format method,
we will change the output
format of the dataset
from Python dictionaries
to Pandas DataFrames.
As you can see in this example,
each row in the dataset is
represented as a DataFrame,
so we can slice the whole dataset
to get a single DataFrame of the corpus.
The way this works under the hood,
is that the datasets library changes
the magic __getitem__
method of the dataset.
The __getitem__ method is a special method
for Python containers that allows you
to specify how indexing works.
In this case, the __getitem__
method of the raw dataset
starts off by returning
a Python dictionary
and then after applying set_format,
we change __getitem__ to
return DataFrames instead.
The Datasets library also
provides a to_pandas method
if you wanna do the format conversion
and slicing of the dataset in one go.
And once you have a DataFrame,
you can find the answers to
all sorts of complex questions
or make plots with your
favorite visualization library.
The only thing to remember
is that once you're done
with your Pandas analysis,
you should reset the output
format back to Arrow tables.
If you don't, you can run into problems
if you try to tokenize your text
because it is no longer represented
as strings in a dictionary.
By resetting the output format
we get back Arrow tables
and we can tokenize without problem.
(whooshing sound)