(air whooshing)
(logo popping)
(metal sliding)
- Memory mapping and streaming.
In this video, we'll take a look
at two core features
of the Datasets library
that allow you to load
and process huge datasets
without blowing up your laptop's CPU.
Nowadays, it's not
uncommon to find yourself
working with multi-GB sized datasets,
especially if you're planning to pretrain
a transformer like BERT
or GPT-2 from scratch.
In these cases, even loading
the data can be a challenge.
For example, the c4
corpus used to pretrain T5
consists of over two terabytes of data.
To handle these large datasets,
the Datasets library is
built on two core features:
the Apache Arrow format
and a streaming API.
Arrow is designed for
high-performance data processing
and represents each table-like dataset
with a column-based format.
As you can see in this
example, column-based formats
group the elements of a table
in consecutive blocks of RAM
and this unlocks fast
access and processing.
Arrow is great at
processing data at any scale
but some datasets are so large
that you can't even fit
them on your hard disk.
So for these cases, the
Datasets library provides
a streaming API that allows
you to progressively download
the raw data one element at a time.
The result is a special object
called an IterableDataset
that we'll see in more detail soon.
Let's start by looking at
why Arrow is so powerful.
The first feature is that
it treats every dataset
as a memory-mapped file.
Now, memory mapping is a mechanism
that maps a portion of a file
or an entire file and disc
to a chunk of virtual memory.
This allows applications
to access segments of
an extremely large file
without having to read the
whole file into memory first.
Another cool feature of Arrow's
memory mapping capabilities
is that it allows multiple processes
to work with the same large dataset
without moving it or
copying it in any way.
This zero-copy feature of Arrow
makes it extremely fast for
iterating over a dataset.
And this example, you
can see that we iterate
over 15 million rows in about a minute
just using a standard laptop.
That's not too bad at all.
Let's now take a look at how
we can stream a large dataset.
The only change you need to make is to set
the streaming=True argument in
the load_dataset() function.
This will return a special
IterableDataset object
which is a bit different
to the Dataset objects
we've seen in other videos.
This object is an iterable,
which means we can't index
it to access elements,
but instead we iterate on it
using the iter and next methods.
This will download and access
a single example from the dataset,
which means you can progressively iterate
through a huge dataset without
having to download it first.
Tokenizing text with a map() method
also works in a similar way.
We first stream the dataset
and then apply the map()
method with the tokenizer.
To get the first tokenized
example, we apply iter and next.
The main difference with
an IterableDataset is that
instead of using a select()
method to return examples,
we use the take() and skip() methods
because we can't index into the dataset.
The take() method returns
the first N examples in the dataset,
while skip(), as you can imagine,
skips the first N and returns the rest.
You can see examples of both
of these methods in action
where we create a validation set
from the first 1000 examples
and then skip those to
create the training set.
(air whooshing)