(transition music)
- Uploading a dataset to the hub.
In this video, we'll take a look
at how you can upload
your very own dataset
to the Hugging Face Hub.
The first thing you need to do
is create a new dataset
repository on the hub.
So, just click on your profile icon
and select the New Dataset button.
Next, we need to assign
an owner of the dataset.
By default, this will be your hub account,
but you can also create datasets
under any organization that you belong to.
Then, we just need to give
the dataset a good name
and specify whether it is a
public or private dataset.
Public datasets can be accessed by anyone
while private datasets
can only be accessed
by you or members of your organization.
And with that, we can go
ahead and create the dataset.
Now that you have an empty
dataset repository on the hub,
the next thing to do is
add some actual data to it.
You can do this with git,
but the easiest way is by
selecting the Upload file button.
And then, you can just go ahead
and upload the files
directly from your machine.
After you've uploaded your files,
you'll see them appear in the repository
under the Files and versions tab.
The last step is to create a dataset card.
Well-documented datasets
are more likely to be useful
to others as they provide
the context to decide
whether the dataset is relevant
or whether there are any biases
or risks associated
with using the dataset.
On the Hugging Face Hub,
this information is stored in
each repositories README file.
There are two main steps
that you should take.
First, you need to create some metadata
that will allow your dataset
to be easily found by others on the hub.
You can create this metadata
using the datasets tagging application,
which we'll link to in
the video description.
Once you've created the metadata,
you can fill out the
rest of the dataset card,
and we provide a template
that we'll also link to in the video.
And once your dataset is on the hub,
you can load it using the
trusty load_dataset function.
Just provide the name of your repository
and a data_files argument,
and you're good to go.
(transition music)