(air whooshing)
- You are at the right place
if you want to understand
what the Byte Pair Encoding
subword tokenization algorithm is,
how to train it
and how the tokenization of a text is done
with this algorithm.
The BPE algorithm
was initially proposed as a
text compression algorithm
but it is also very well suited
as a tokenizer for your language models.
The idea of BPE is to divide words
into a sequence of 'subword units'
which are units that appear
frequently in a reference corpus
which is, the corpus we used to train it.
How is a BPE tokenizer trained?
First of all, we have to
get a corpus of texts.
We will not train our
tokenizer on this raw text
but we will first normalize it
then pre-tokenize it.
As the pre-tokenization
divides the text into a list of words,
we can represent our corpus in another way
by gathering together the same words
and by maintaining a counter,
here represented in blue.
To understand how the training works,
we consider this toy corpus
composed of the following words:
huggingface, hugging, hug, hugger, etc.
BPE is an algorithm that starts
with an initial vocabulary
and then increases it to the desired size.
To build the initial vocabulary,
we start by separating
each word of the corpus
into a list of elementary
units that compose them,
here, the characters.
We list in our vocabulary all
the characters that appear
and that will constitute
our initial vocabulary.
Let's now see how to increase it.
We return to our split corpus,
we will go through the words one by one
and count all the
occurrences of token pairs.
The first pair is composed
of the token 'h' and 'u',
the second 'u' and 'g',
and we continue like that until
we have the complete list.
Once we know all the pairs
and their frequency of appearance,
we will choose the one that
appears the most frequently.
Here it is the pair composed
of the letters 'l' and 'e'.
We note our first merging rule
and we add the new
token to our vocabulary.
We can then apply this
merging rule to our splits.
You can see that we have
merged all the pairs of tokens
composed of the tokens 'l' and 'e'.
And now, we just have to
reproduce the same steps
with our new splits.
We calculate the frequency of occurrence
of each pair of tokens,
we select the pair with
the highest frequency,
we note it in our merge rules,
we add the new one token the vocabulary
and then we merge all the pairs of tokens
composed of the token 'le'
and 'a' into our splits.
And we can repeat this operation
until we reach the
desired vocabulary size.
Here, we stopped when our
vocabulary reached 21 tokens.
We can see now that
the words of our corpus
are now divided into far fewer tokens
than at the beginning of the training.
And that our algorithm
has learned the radicals 'hug' and 'learn'
and also the verbal ending 'ing'.
Now that we have learned our vocabulary
and merging rules, we
can tokenize new texts.
For example,
if we want to tokenize the word 'hugs',
first we'll divide it
into elementary units
so it became a sequence of characters.
Then, we'll go through our merge rules
until we have one we can apply.
Here, we can merge the
letters 'h' and 'u'.
And here, we can merge 2 tokens
to get the new token 'hug'.
When we get to the end of our merge rules,
the tokenization is finished.
And that's it.
I hope that now the BPE algorithm
has no more secret for you!
(air whooshing)