(air whooshing)
- In this video,
we will study together
'the Unigram Language Model
subword tokenization algorithm'.
The overall training strategy
of a Unigram Language Model tokenizer
is to start with a very large vocabulary
and then to remove
tokens at each iteration
until we reach the desired size.
At each iteration,
we will calculate a loss
on our training corpus
thanks to the Unigram model.
As the loss calculation depends
on the available vocabulary,
we can use it to choose how
to reduce the vocabulary.
So we look at the evolution of the loss
by removing in turn each
token from the vocabulary.
We will choose to remove the p-percents
which increase the loss the less.
Before going further
in the explanation of
the training algorithm,
I need to explain what
is an Unigram model.
The Unigram Language Model
is a type of Statistical Language Modem.
A Statistical Language Model
will assign a probability to a text
considering that the text is
in fact a sequence of tokens.
The simplest sequences
of tokens to imagine
are the words that compose the
sentence or the characters.
The particularity of
Unigram Language Model
is that it assumes that
the occurrence of each word
is independent of its previous word.
This assumption allows us to write
that the probability of a text
is equal to the product
of the probabilities
of the tokens that compose it.
It should be noted here that
it is a very simple model
which would not be adapted
to the generation of text
since this model would always
generate the same token,
the one which has the
greatest probability.
Nevertheless, to do tokenization,
this model is very useful to us
because it can be used
to estimate the relative
likelihood of different phrases.
We are now ready
to return to our explanation
of the training algorithm.
Let's say that we have
as a training corpus
with 10 times the word hug,
12 times the word pug,
5 times the word lug,
4 times bug
and 5 times dug.
As said earlier,
the training starts with a big vocabulary.
Obviously, as we are using a toy corpus,
this vocabulary will not be that big
but it should show you the principle.
A first method is to list all
the possible strict substrings
and that's what we'll do here.
We could also have used the BPE algorithm
with a very large vocabulary size
but for now, the strict
substrings are enough.
The training of the Unigram tokenizer
is based on the
Expectation-Maximization method.
At each iteration,
we estimate the
probabilities of the tokens
of the vocabulary
and then we remove the p-percent of tokens
that minimize the loss on the corpus
and which do not belong
to the basic character
as we want to keep in our final vocabulary
the basic characters to be
able to tokenize any word.
Let's go for it!
The probability of a
token simply estimated
by the number of appearance of this token
in our training corpus
divided by the total number of
appearance of all the tokens.
We could use this vocabulary
to tokenize our words
according to the Unigram model.
We will do it together
to understand two things:
how we tokenize a word
with a Unigram model
and how the loss is
calculated on our corpus.
The Unigram LM tokenization
of our text 'Hug'
will be the one with the highest
probability of occurrence
according to our Unigram model.
To find it, the simplest way to proceed
would be to list all the
possible segmentations
of our text 'Hug',
calculate the probability of
each of these segmentations
and then choose the one with
the highest probability.
With the current vocabulary,
two tokenizations get
exactly the same probability.
So we choose one of them
and keep in memory the
associated probability.
To compute the loss on
our training corpus,
we need to tokenize as we just did
all the remaining words in the corpus.
The loss is then the sum over
all the words in the corpus
of the frequency of occurrence of the word
multiplied by the opposite
of the log of the probability
associated with the
tokenization of the word.
We obtain here a loss of 170.
Remember, our initial goal
was to reduce the vocabulary.
To do this, we will remove
a token from the vocabulary
and calculate the associated loss.
Let's remove for example, the token 'ug'.
We notice that the tokenization for 'hug'
with the letter 'h' and the
tuple 'ug' is now impossible.
Nevertheless, as we saw earlier
that two tokenizations
had the same probability,
we can still choose the
remaining tokenization
with a probability of 1.10e-2.
The tokenizations of the
other words of the vocabulary
also remain unchanged.
And finally, even if we
remove the token 'ug'
from our vocabulary the
loss remains equal to 170.
For this first iteration,
if we continue the calculation,
we would notice that we
could remove any token
without it impacting the loss.
We will therefore choose at
random to remove the token 'ug'
before starting a second iteration.
So we estimate again the
probability of each token
before calculating the impact
of each token on the loss.
For example, if we remove now
the token composed of
the letters 'h' and 'u',
there is only one possible
tokenization left for hug.
The tokenization of the
other words of the vocabulary
is not changed.
In the end,
we obtain by removing the token
composed of the letters 'h'
and 'u' from the vocabulary,
a loss of 168.
Finally, to choose which token to remove,
we will for each remaining
token of the vocabulary,
which is not an elementary token,
calculate the associated loss.
Then, compare these losses between them.
The token which we will remove
is the token which impacts
the least the loss,
here the token 'bu'.
We had mentioned at the
beginning of the video
that at each iteration we could remove
p-percent of the tokens by iteration.
The second token that could
be removed at this iteration
is the token 'du'.
And that's it.
We just have to repeat these steps
until we get the vocabulary
of the desired size.
One last thing.
In practice, when we tokenize
a word with a Unigram model,
we don't compute the
set of probabilities of
all the possible splits of a word
before comparing them to keep the best one
but we use the Viterbi algorithm
which is much more efficient way to do it.
And that's it!
I hope that this example
has allowed you to better understand
the Unigram tokenization algorithm.
(air whooshing)