(screen whooshing)
(sticker popping)
- In this video, we take a look
at the mysterious sounding
metric called perplexity.
You might have encountered perplexity
when reading about generative models.
You can see two examples here,
one from the original transformer paper,
"Attention is all you need,"
and the other one from the
more recent GPT-2 paper.
Perplexity is a common metric
to measure the performance
of language models.
The smaller its value, the
better the performance.
But what does it actually mean
and how can we calculate it?
A very common quantity in machine learning
is the likelihood.
We can calculate the likelihood
as the product of each
token's probability.
What this means is that for each token,
we use the language model
to predict its probability
based on the previous tokens.
In the end, we multiply all probabilities
to get the likelihood.
With the likelihood,
we can calculate another
important quantity,
the cross-entropy.
You might have already
heard about cross-entropy
when looking at loss function.
It is often used as a loss
function in classification.
In language modeling, we
predict the next token
based on the previous token,
which is also a classification task.
Therefore, if we want to calculate
the cross-entropy of an example,
we can simply pass it to the model
with its inputs as labels.
The loss then corresponds
to the cross-entropy.
We are now only a single operation away
from calculating the perplexity.
By exponentiating the cross-entropy,
we get the perplexity.
So you see that the
perplexity is closely related
to the loss.
Plugging in previous results
shows that this is
equivalent to exponentiating
the negative average lock
probability of each token.
Keep in mind that the
loss is only a weak proxy
for a model's ability
to generate quality text
and the same is true for perplexity.
For this reason, one
usually also calculates
more sophisticated metrics
such as BLEU or ROUGE on generative tasks.
(screen whooshing)