(air whooshing)
(smiley snapping)
- What is domain adaptation?
When fine-tuning a pre-trained
model on a new dataset,
the fine-tuned model we
obtain will make predictions
that are attuned to this new dataset.
When the two models are
trained with the same task,
we can then compare their
predictions on the same input.
The predictions of the two
models will be different
in a way that reflects the differences
between the two datasets,
a phenomenon we call domain adaptation.
Let's look at an example
with masked language modeling
by comparing the outputs of the
pre-trained DistilBERT model
with the version fine-tuned
in chapter 7 of the course, linked below.
The pre-trained model
makes generic predictions,
whereas the fine-tuned model
has its first two
predictions linked to cinema.
Since it was fine-tuned on
a movie reviews dataset,
it's perfectly normal to see
it adapted its suggestions like this.
Notice how it keeps the same prediction
as the pre-trained model afterward.
Even if the fine-tuned model
adapts to the new dataset,
it's not forgetting what
it was pre-trained on.
This is another example
on a translation task.
On top, we use a pre-trained
French/English model,
and at the bottom, the version
we fine-tuned in chapter 7.
The top model is pre-trained
on lots of texts,
and leaves technical English terms,
like plugin and email,
unchanged in the translation.
Both are perfectly
understood by French people.
The dataset picked for the
fine-tuning is a dataset
of technical texts where
special attention was picked
on translating everything in French.
As a result, the fine-tuned
model picked that habit
and translated both plugin and email.
(air whooshing)