(whoosh)
- In this video we'll
learn the first things to
do when you get an error.
This is not throwing your
laptop through the window.
Let's say we want to use the
question answering pipeline
on a particular model and
we get the following error.
Errors in Python can appear overwhelming
because you get so much
information printed out
but that's because Python
is trying to help you
the best it can to solve your problem.
In this video, we'll see how to interpret
the error report we get.
The first thing to notice at the very top
is that Python shows
you with a clear arrow
the line of code that triggers the error
so you don't have to fiddle with your code
and remove random lines to figure out
where the error comes from.
You have the answer in
front of you right here.
The errors you see below
are a part of the code
Python tried to execute while
running the instruction.
Here we are inside the pipeline function
and zero came on this line
while trying to execute
the function "check_tasks,"
which then raised the
KeyError we see displayed.
Note that Python tells you exactly
where the function it's executing lives,
so if you feel adventurous
you can even go inspect the source code.
This whole thing is
called the "Traceback."
If you're running your code on Colab
the Traceback is automatically minimized,
so you have to click to expand it.
At the very end of the Traceback
you finally get the actual error message.
The first thing you should
do when encountering
an error is to read that error message.
Here it's telling us it doesn't know
the question answering task
and helpfully gives us the list
of supported tasks in which we can see
that "question-answering" actually is.
Looking more closely though,
we used an underscore to
surprise the two words
when the task is written with a minus,
so we should fix that.
Now let's retry our code with
the tags properly written
and what is happening today?
Another error.
As we said before, we
go look at the bottom
to read the actual error message.
It's telling us that we should check
our model is a correct model identifier,
so let's hop onto hf.co/models.
We can see our model listed there
in the ones available
for question answering.
The difference is that
it's spelled "distilbert"
with one L, and we use two,
so let's fix that.
We finally get our results.
If our error is more complex,
you might need to use the Python debugger.
Check out the videos below to learn how.