- [Instructor] Using the
Python debugger in a notebook.
In this video, we'll learn
how to use the Python debugger
in a Jupyter Notebook or a Colab.
For this example, we are running code
from the token classification section,
downloading the Conll dataset,
looking a little bit at data,
before loading a tokenizer
to preprocess the whole dataset.
Check out the section of
the course linked below
for more information.
Once this is done,
we try to load eight features
of the training dataset,
and then batch them together,
using tokenizer.pad,
and we get the following error.
We use PyTorch here,
with return_tensors="pt"
but you will get the same
error with TensorFlow.
As we have seen in the "How
to debug an error?" video,
the error message is at
the end of the traceback.
Here, it indicates us
we should use padding,
which we are actually trying to do.
So this is not useful at all,
and we will need to go a little deeper
to debug the problem.
Fortunately, you can
use the Python debugger
at any time you get an
error in a Jupyter Notebook
by typing the magic
command, debug, in a cell.
Don't forget the percent at the beginning.
When executing that cell,
you go to the very bottom of the traceback
where you can type commands
that will help you debug your script.
The first two commands you should learn,
are u and d, for up and down.
Typing u and enter will
take you up one step
in the traceback to the
previous instruction.
Typing d and then enter will take you
one step down in the traceback.
Going up twice, we get to the
point the error was reached.
The third command to learn for
the debugger is p, for print.
It allows you to print any value you want.
For instance, typing p
return_tensors and enter,
we see the value pt that we
pass to the bad function.
We can also have a look
at the batch outputs
this batch line coding object gets.
The batch outputs dictionary
is a bit hard to dig in to,
so let's dive into smaller pieces of it.
Inside the debugger you can
not only print any variable
but also evaluate any expression,
for instance, we can have a
look at the input_ids keys
this batch_outputs object.
Or at the labels keys of
Those labels are definitely weird:
they are of various sizes,
which we can actually confirm, if we want,
by printing the size with
the least compression.
This is because the pad
method of the tokenizer
only takes care of the tokenizer outputs:
input IDs, attention
mask, and token type IDs,
so we have to pad the labels ourselves
before trying to create
a tensor with them.
Once you are ready to
exit the Python debugger,
you can press q and enter for quit.
One way to fix the error
is to manually pad the
labels to the longest.
Another way is to use a data collator
specifically designed
for token classification.
You can also use a
Python debugger directly
in the terminal.
Check out the video
link below to learn how.