(title whooshes)
(logo pops)
- How to ask a question on
the Hugging Face forums?
If you have a general question
or are looking to debug your code,
the forums are the place to ask.
In this video we will teach you
how to write a good question,
to maximize the chances
you will get an answer.
First things first, to
login on the forums,
you need a Hugging Face account.
If you haven't created one already,
go to hf.co and click sign up.
There is also a direct link below.
Fill your email and password,
then continue the steps
to pick your username
and update a profile picture.
Once this is done, go to
discuss.huggingface.co,
link below, and click log in.
Use the same login information as
for the Hugging Face website.
You can search the forums by clicking
on the magnifying glass.
Someone may have already asked
your question in a topic.
If you find you can't post
a new topic as a new user,
it may be because of the antispam filters.
Make sure you spend some
time reading existing topics
to deactivate it.
When you're sure your question
hasn't been asked yet,
click on the new topic button.
For this example, we'll
use the following code,
that produces an error,
as we saw in the "What to do
when I get an error" video.
The first step is to pick a
category for our new topic.
Since our error has to do
with the Transformers library,
we pick this category.
Next, choose a title that
summarizes your error well.
Don't be too vague or users
that get the same error you did
in the future won't be
able to find your topic.
Once you have finished
typing your topic title,
make sure the question
hasn't been answered
in the topics Discourse suggests you.
Click on the cross to remove that window
when you have double-checked.
This is an example of what not
to do when posting an error.
The message is very vague,
so no one else will be able
to guess what went wrong
for you, and it tags too many people.
Tagging people, especially moderators,
might have the opposite
effect of what you want.
As you send them a notification,
and they get plenty,
they will probably not
bother replying to you,
and users you didn't tag will
probably ignore the questions,
since they see tagged users.
Only tag a user when you
are completely certain
they are the best place
to answer your question.
Be precise in your text, and
if you have an error coming
from a specific piece of
code, include that code
in your post.
To make sure your post looks
good, place your question
between three backticks like this.
You can check on the right
how your post will appear once posted.
If your question is about an error,
it's even better to
include the full traceback.
As explained in the "What to
do when I get an error" video,
expand the traceback if you're on Colab.
Like for the code, put it
between two lines
containing three backticks
for proper formatting.
Our last advice is to remember to be nice.
A "Please," and a "Thank
you" will go a long way
into getting others to help you.
With all that done properly,
your question should get
an answer pretty quickly.
(title whooshes)
(title fizzles)